♪ ♪
[spooky music]
[诡异的音乐]
- Bonjour, art lovers.
- 你好，艺术爱好者。
Tonight, for your
viewing enjoyment,
今晚，为你
观赏享受，
we present a portrait
painted in shades of greed.
我们呈现一幅肖像
被描绘成贪婪的色调。
- Ahh!
Another day,
- 啊！
又一天，
another whole bunch of dollars!
又一大笔钱！
[laughs]
[笑]
[metallic clinking]
Hmm?
[金属叮当作响]
嗯？
Ooh, a quarter!
哦，四分之一！
Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme.
给我，给我，给我，给我。
Whew, come back here, you!
呼呼，你快回来吧！
Hey, hey, where are you going?
嘿嘿嘿，你要去哪儿？
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[exhales]
Whew.
[呼气]
呼。
[sighs]
[叹气]
Eh?
呃？
Yah!
[blubbering]
啊！
[哭泣]
[ding]
[叮]
[struggling efforts]
【奋斗努力】
Huh?
啊？
Ooh, this quarter is
really making me work.
哦，这个季度是
真的让我工作。
[clinks]
[叮当声]
Huh?
Hey, get back here!
啊？
嘿，快回来吧！
Ugh!
啊!
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Greetings, stranger.
- Ahh!
- 你好，陌生人。
- 啊！
Welcome to my
Emporium of Wonders.
欢迎来到我的
奇迹商场。
Can I interest you
in a traditional
我可以让你感兴趣吗
在传统的
Klopnodian Spladunker?
克洛普诺德斯普拉德克？
Or perhaps a lightly
used Flooner?
或者也许轻轻地
用过弗洛纳吗？
- No thanks, old timer.
- 不，谢谢，老家伙。
I just want me quarter.
我只想要四分之一。
It seems to have hopped
into your pay phone here.
好像跳了
请输入您的付费电话。
- Oh, I see.
- 我懂了。
Well I have no power
to retrieve your coin,
好吧，我没有权力
取回你的硬币，
but I can let you
have the payphone
但我可以让你
有公用电话
for the low, low price of...
为了低廉的价格...
free.
自由的。
- Free?
I'll take it!
- 自由的？
我要买它！
- But be warned, that
payphone comes with a curse.
- 但请注意，
公用电话带有诅咒。
[thunder booms]
[woman screams]
[雷霆轰鸣]
[女人尖叫]
- Really?
How much does the curse cost?
- 真的吗？
诅咒要花多少钱？
- What?
No, the curse is free.
- 什么？
不，诅咒是免费的。
It comes with the phone.
它随手机一起提供。
- Well then!
- 那么！
I'll take the curse, too!
我也来承受诅咒吧！
[chuckling]
- Heed my Kapritzka!
[轻笑]
- 听我的卡普里兹卡！
Beware the call of the porch!
当心门廊的呼唤！
Beware!
提防！
Ah, forget it.
啊，算了。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Listen up, happy Krustomers!
听着，快乐的 Krustomers！
For the low price of
a quarter, now you, too,
对于低廉的价格
四分之一，现在你也是，
can make that important call
可以拨打那个重要电话
while you're eating
a Krabby Patty!
当你吃饭的时候
蟹肉饼！
[ringing]
[铃声]
Ahoy, there. Krusty Krab.
啊嘿，在那里。蟹堡王。
Eugene Krabs,
proprietor, speaking.
尤金·克拉布斯，
楼主，说话了。
- [evil laughter]
- [邪恶的笑声]
Give away your
Krabby Patties!
放弃你的
蟹肉饼！
Give them all away!
把他们全都扔掉！
- [gasps] What kind of obscene
phone call is this?
- [喘气] 什么样的淫秽
电话是这个吗？
When I find out who you are,
I'm gonna--
当我知道你是谁时
我要--
Oh!
哦！
Hey!
嘿！
[line trilling]
[行颤音]
Must give patties away.
一定要送肉饼。
[cash register dings]
[收银机叮叮声]
[all exclaim]
No money.
[所有人惊呼]
没有钱。
Patties free!
馅饼免费！
- Free patties?
- 免费肉饼？
Oh, Mr. Krabs!
哦，蟹老板！
You finally found
your inner generosity.
你终于找到了
你内心的慷慨。
Hooray!
万岁！
Krabby Patties for everyone!
蟹肉饼送给大家！
Wha! Yow!
世界卫生大会！哟！
The Krab is picking up the tab!
螃蟹要买单了！
[all hooting and hollering]
[所有的叫喊声和叫喊声]
- All free.
- 全部免费。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
[all munching]
[全都在咀嚼]
- [evil laughter]
- [邪恶的笑声]
- [blubbering]
- [哭泣]
Huh? What just happened?
啊？刚刚发生了什么？
Oh, boy! A quarter!
哦，孩子！四分之一！
I knew this thing
would pay off!
我知道这件事
会有回报的！
- Patties here!
- [yelps]
- 这里有馅饼！
- [尖叫声]
- Free patties!
- 免费肉饼！
Get your patties
while they're hot!
拿你的肉饼
趁他们还热的时候！
Get 'em while they're free!
趁他们有空的时候获取它们！
- Free?
[woman screams]
- 自由的？
[女人尖叫]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
SpongeBob! There's no free
lunches at the Krusty Krab!
海绵宝宝！没有免费的
在蟹堡王吃午餐！
[all clamoring]
Have you gone insane?
[全都吵闹]
你疯了吗？
Get back in the kitchen
and stitch
回到厨房
并缝合
these patty halves
back together
这些半块肉饼
回到一起
so we can sell 'em again.
这样我们就可以再次出售它们。
[sign poofs]
[噗]
- [groans]
It was too good to last.
- [呻吟]
它太好了，无法持久。
[ringing]
[铃声]
- Krusty Krab, Eugene--
[groans]
- 蟹堡王，尤金 -
[呻吟]
- [evil laughter]
Now give away your money!
- [邪恶的笑声]
现在就把你的钱捐出去吧！
Every last cent!
每一分钱！
- Must give away money.
- 必须捐钱。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[whistle blares]
[汽笛声]
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Give away all money, Boy-O!
- 把所有的钱都捐出去，Boy-O！
- But you just said that--
- 但你刚刚说过--
Oh, I knew you were
only kidding, Mr. Krabs!
哦，我知道你是
开玩笑吧，蟹老板！
You really are generous!
[chuckles]
你还真是大方啊！
[笑声]
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
[chuckles]
Another quarter!
[笑声]
又一个季度！
I love this phone!
[cash register dings]
我喜欢这款手机！
[收银机叮叮声]
[all clamoring]
- Whoo! [laughing]
[全都吵闹]
- 呼！ [笑]
Whee!
[all cheering]
哎哟！
[大家欢呼]
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
What are you doing
with me money?
你在做什么
跟我有钱吗？
- Well, I thought you
told me to, Mr. Krabs.
- 嗯，我以为你
蟹老板告诉我的。
I--oh, I don't understand.
我——哦，我不明白。
[phone ringing]
[电话铃声]
- Uh! Ooh!
- And now, Krabs,
- 呃！哦！
- 现在，蟹蟹，
give away the Krusty Krab!
赠送蟹堡王！
[evil laughter]
[邪恶的笑声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Yes!
With this laser cannon,
是的！
有了这门激光炮，
I can finally blast Krabs!
我终于可以炸螃蟹了！
Huh?
啊？
Homina-wha?
霍米纳-什么？
- Here his deed to Krusty Krab.
- 这是他对蟹堡王的契约。
She's all yours.
她就是你的了。
- Something doesn't
seem right here.
- 有些东西没有
似乎就在这里。
But like Granny Plankton
always says,
但就像浮游生物奶奶一样
总是说，
never look a gift snail
under the shell!
永远不要看礼物蜗牛
在壳下！
I win!
[laughs]
我赢了！
[笑]
I'm the greatest!
我是最伟大的！
Huh?
[clank]
啊？
[铮铮]
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
[hypnotic music]
[催眠音乐]
- Ooh!
[laughs]
- 哦！
[笑]
Huh?
啊？
Ohh, what the--
where's me quarter?
哦，那是什么——
我在哪里？
- [evil laughter]
- [grunting]
- [邪恶的笑声]
- [咕哝]
- Perhaps generosity
is its own reward?
- 也许是慷慨
是它自己的奖励吗？
- Never!
- [laughs]
- 绝不！
- [笑]
- [grunts, laughs]
- [咕哝，大笑]
Huh? Ooh.
啊？哦。
- Uh--
- 呃--
[both growling]
[双方咆哮]
- Huh?
- 啊？
[gasps]
[喘气]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Hey, what's the big idea?
- 嘿，有什么好主意吗？
And where is that quarter
you owe--
那四分之一在哪里
你欠——
- I'm free!
Ha-ha!
- 我有空了！
哈哈！
[muttering] Um--
[嘀咕] 嗯——
Hey kid, lend me
a quarter for the bus?
嘿小子，借给我吧
乘公共汽车需要四分之一吗？
- Sure thing, Mr. Demon!
- 当然可以，恶魔先生！
- I'm finally free!
- 我终于自由了！
[laughs]
[笑]
[phone ringing]
[电话铃声]
- Well, this ain't so bad.
- 嗯，这还不错。
Steady work,
and plenty of quarters!
工作稳定，
还有充足的宿舍！
[laughs]
A crab could get used to this!
[笑]
螃蟹可能会习惯这个！
[crashing]
Whoa!
[崩溃]
哇！
Hey! What's going on?
[thud]
嘿！这是怎么回事？
[砰]
- [grunting]
[clanging]
- [咕哝]
[叮叮当当]
- Hey, Squidward,
- 嘿，章鱼哥，
get that hunk of junk
out of here, would you?
得到那一大堆垃圾
离开这里，你愿意吗？
Come on.
快点。
- Gladly.
- 很高兴。
[crashing]
[崩溃]
- Hello, anyone wanna
make a call?
- 你好，有人想要吗
打电话？
Only costs a quarter.
只需要四分之一的费用。
Ooh, barnacles!
哦，藤壶！
[foghorn blares]
[bell dinging]
[雾号声]
[铃声]
- Sometimes a free phone
- 有时有免费电话
comes at a very high price,
价格非常高，
and sometimes the cheapskates
有时还有小气鬼
are the ones who get stuck
with the bill
是那些被困住的人
与账单
here in "The Tidal Zone."
这里是“潮汐区”。
[phone ringing]
[电话铃声]
Hello?
你好？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Must give
away one more story.
必须给
还有一个故事。
The story of a grandpa
adrift in space and time.
爷爷的故事
在空间和时间中漂泊。
The story of a sea star who
is lost in "The Tidal Zone."
一个海星的故事
迷失在“潮汐区”。
[dial tone blaring]
[拨号音刺耳]
- [yelling]
- [大喊]